# Tyler Maxwell

(818)809-8653 • tylermaxwell661@gmail.com • LinkedIn • github/tmax818 • www.tylermaxwell.co

#### **STATEMENT**

Full stack web developer with a passion for making technology accessible to everyone. Experience several web development frameworks coupled with a background in law enforcement and education has cultivated an eclectic and pragmatic skill set. Fascination with web development has been a natural outgrowth of my commitment to lifelong learning and enduring love of technology. Strong skills in problem solving and leadership cultivated during my 20 plus years of diverse work experience would help organizations grow and thrive. Immune to pepper spray and teargas.

#### **SKILLS**

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | NodeJS | Express | React | Redux | Python | Flask | Jinja | Django | MySQL | Java | Spring |
Spring Boot | Maven | Git | GitHub | C/C++ | Ruby | Ruby on Rails | Sinatra | Jest | Bash scripting | Linux | AWS |

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Instructor | Coding Dojo

November 2021 - present

- Delivered in person and online instruction to a group of 10 to 30 students.
- Evaluated student progress and understanding of course material.
- Provided instruction in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Flask, MySQL, Java, Spring,.

#### Instructor | Nucamp

February 2020 - February 2021

- Delivered remote instruction to groups of 8 to 12 students.
- Provided instruction in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, React, and Redux,.
- Monitored student progress using formal and informal assessment tools both proscribed and self generated.

## Facilitator | Girls Who Code

June 2019 - August 2019

- Delivered Computer Science lessons while maintaining an engaging and accessible classroom.
- Managed and adapted instruction based on student proficiency with computer science concepts.
- Supervised a Teaching Assistant in classroom management, instruction and logistical tasks.

## Training Engineer | Schneider National

Aug 2013 - Jun 2015

- Maintained positive customer relationships through open lines of honest communication.
- Trained new employees in safety and maintenance standards.
- Provided training for new employees over seven consecutive days.

## Social Studies Teacher | Los Angeles Unified School District

August 2007 - June 2012

- · Designed and taught curriculum for Social Science for middle and high school students
- · Collaborated with colleagues in other disciplines in order to incorporate STEM in the Social Science curriculum.
- Created and maintained discipline system in the capacity of temporary dean of students.

### Deputy Sheriff | Los Angeles County Sheriff's Department

September 1999 - August 2007

- Provided law enforcement services in a variety of venues.
- · Prepared and maintained written and digital logs and reports for law enforcement records and court proceedings.
- Functioned as an integral member of a criminal court staff by providing security and assisting in daily court proceedings.

## **EDUCATION**

Secondary Teaching Credential |

June 2006 National University, Los Angeles, CA

BA Philosophy |

December 2001 University of California, Los Angeles, CA

## **TRAINING & CERTIFICATIONS**

Flatiron School | Full Stack Web Development

December 2018

• emphasis on Ruby on Rails and React |

Comptia | A+ December 2023

• estimated time of completion: December 2023